Claudia Ruiz

Product Designer

🚺 in/claudiaux

in ClaudiaRuizUX

claudiaruizux.ga

@ClaudiaRuizUX

claudiaruizux@gmail.com

Sydney AEDT | Can Relocate

Hello, I am Claudia Ruiz and currently working as a product designer for a data company in the real estate and banking industry. Started in the field as a graphic designer, moved from web development to UX designer to now learning emerging technologies.

My experience (10y+) spans from startups to large organizations in media, fintech, and big data, preferring using data to drive design decisions while balancing the best level of quality with quick releases to continue the measure-improve cycle.

Through my time practicing design, I learned that building the right design case comes from a holistic understanding of people, technology, and systems. I stay fascinated by the interdisciplinary nature of the field, human factors, and emerging tech. Today my goal is to work with a very cool team on a meaningful project that supports decentralization.

Partners & Clients

















Claudia Ruiz

Product Designer

🕠 in/claudiaux

in ClaudiaRuizUX

claudiaruizux.ga

@ClaudiaRuizUX

claudiaruizux@gmail.com

Sydney AEDT | Can Relocate

Experience

CoreLogic | Product Designer

Jun 2017 - Present | Sydney, Australia

Leading Australia & New Zealand product design. A mix of workshops, research and co-design activities. I've repositioned the brand and influenced development of greenfield products for the valuation and banking industry.

The Link Group | UX Designer

Oct 2015 - Jun 2017 | Sydney, Australia

Designed and validated products and services workflows for a fund management system and a superannuation platform.

The New Zealad Herald | Senior Product Designer

Feb 2011 - Sept 2015 | Auckland, New Zealand

Worked collaboratevly with reporters to explore new ways to cover new stories with emerging technologies.

Moko Digital | Visual Designer & Developer

Nov 2009 - Dec 2010 | Auckland, New Zealand

Interviewed customers to understand their needs to explore design and develop solutions for their digital presence.

Trio Group | Multimedia Designer

Apr 2007 - Nov 2009 | Auckland, New Zealand

Design and front-end development.

Languages

Spanish, Portuguese & English

Education & Courses

Fundamentals of Bitcoin

Pomp's Crypto Academy | 2021

Foundations in Design Thinking

IDEO | 2020

Service Design

Academy Xi | 2020

Decentralised Experiences

Academy Xi | ConsenSys | 2019

Psychology (Single Subject)

Swinburne University of Technology | 2016

Design Systems

Nielsen Norman Group | 2016

User Experience Design & Research

Billy Blue College of Design | 2015

Diploma in Digital Media

(with distinction)

Media Design School | 2008 - 2010

Awards

Financial Service App of the year

MAX Awards | 2017

Best Innovation in Multimedia

Canon Media Award | 2012

Student Panel Board

at Media Design School | 2011